Taras Holovatch

Curriculum Vitae

May, 2024

E-mail: <u>holovatch@gmail.com</u>

Skype: skaramush.

Phone number: +38 (067) 941-39-85 Date of birth: June 28, 1985 Language knowledge: Ukrainian – native

English, technical English – fluently

Location: Lviv, Ukraine

Will relocate: No

Summary of Qualifications:

10+ years of experience in software development, including 7+ years on Python based projects, using Django / Flask / Falcon / common sense & before that 3+ years on PHP based projects, using Symphony / Zend / Magento / common sense.

Skills:

Programming Languages: Python, PHP, Javascript, C++ basics, bash basics, R basics,

HTML/XML/CSS

Frameworks, platforms, libraries: Django, Flask, Falcon, Odoo, Celery, React, Electron, Symfony,

Magento, Zend, jQuery, RStudio Shiny, AngularJS basics

RDBMS / data storage: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, memcached, SQLite, RabbitMQ

Tools: Docker, Apache, nginx, wsgi, Vagrant, Jenkins

Operation systems/environments: Ubuntu, CentOs, Red Hat, AWS, Heroku

Work Experience:

January 2020 - January 2022: Software Engineer — freelance, Lviv, Ukraine

February 2018 - September 2019: Software Engineer/Lead — JetSoftPro, Lviv, Ukraine

February 2016 - July 2017: Software Engineer — CoreValue, Lviv, Ukraine

July 2014 – January 2016: Software Engineer/Team Lead — LvivSoft, Lviv, Ukraine

December 2011 - June 2014: Software Engineer — MalkosUA, Lviv, Ukraine

Education:

2008-2011 PhD in Physics, Coventry University (UK) & UHP Nancy-1 University (France)

2002-2007 BC, Specialist in Applied Mathematics & Informatics

Ivan Franko Lviv National University (Ukraine)

Projects (in reverse chronological order):

#12 Flexit

Description: Web and desktop solutions for air handling manufacturing.

Duration: 1 year / **Team size**: 3 team members

Responsibilities: Providing solutions, back-end/front-end development

Skills Used: Python, PostgreSQL, Javascript, React, Docker, AWS, Celery, Heroku

#11 BJet

Description: Comprehensive cloud solution for business development and management.

Accounting, logistics, analytic dashboards, CRM, HRMS, etc.

Duration: 1 year / **Team size**: 10 team members

Responsibilities: Back-end/front-end development, designing highly available solutions, leading

Skills Used: Python, PostgreSQL, Odoo, Javascript, XML

#10 No Name (contract limitations)

Description: Document management system for one of Big Four accounting firms

Duration: 1 year / **Team size**: 10 team members

Responsibilities: Back-end development

Skills Used: Python, Docker, AWS

#9 Appresso AS

Description: Bunch of scalable web applications built on top of Python/Django

Duration: 1 year / **Team size**: 4-5 team members **Responsibilities**: Back-end/front-end development

Skills Used: Python, PostgreSQL, React, Docker, AWS, Celery, Heroku

#8 No Name (contract limitations)

Description: Application to create 3D objects from set of photos.

Duration: 3 months / **Team size**: alone

Responsibilities: Back-end/front-end development

Skills Used: Python, Falcon, Javascript, Agisoft PhotoScan

#7 Internal HRMS/CRM

Description: Internal HRMS and CRM customization & integration.

Duration: 1.5 years / **Team size**: 1-2 team members

Responsibilities: Back-end/front-end development, code review **Skills Used**: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, Docker, Sentrifugo, SuiteCRM

#6 Supporting data science team

Duration: half a year / **Team size**: 10 team members

Responsibilities: Providing software development expertise, knowledge sharing, etc

Skills Used: Python, R, google, data science models, common sense

#5 Trov (https://www.trov.com)

Description: Web data analysis dashboard for insurance company.

Duration: half a year / **Team size**: 10 team members

Responsibilities:

- Back-end/front-end development
- Data analysis
- DevOps, ETL data migration

Skills Used: Python, R, bash, RStudio Shiny, MySQL, JavaScript, Docker, AWS

#4 No Name (contract limitations)

Description: Health care management Web application.

Duration: half a year / **Team size**: 5-10 team members

Responsibilities: Back-end/front-end development, maintenance & bug fixing

Skills Used: Python, Django, PostgreSQL, MSSQL, JavaScript, Jquery, AJAX, HTML, CSS, PHP

#3 Wondermall (http://www.wondermall.com)

Description: Shopping mall for mobile devices **Duration**: 1.5 years / **Team size**: 16 team members

Responsibilities:

- · Backend development: creating services that scrape, parse & build HTTP requests,
- · Backend maintenance, bug fixing, implementing utilities for QA team
- Mentoring. Delegating jobs. Ensuring they are done. Code review.

Skills Used: Python 2, HTTP, Chrome Extensions, common sense

#2 Recyclebank (http://www.recyclebank.com)

Description: Web project, service oriented architecture, 4ml of customers

Duration: 2 years / **Team size**: 15-30 team members

Responsibilities:

- · Back-end development, maintenance & bug fixing
- Integrating with external services and mobile applications
- Migrating data from DB to external services & vice versa

Skills Used: PHP 5, Magento, Symfony, MySQL, Doctrine, JavaScript, Jquery, AJAX, HTML, XML, CSS, Redis, Gearman, C++

#1 No name (contract limitations)

Description: Data oriented project with multiple MySQL databases.

Duration: 3 months / **Team size**: 4 team members

Responsibilities:

- · Creating reports with dynamic parameters directly from DB views & store procedures results
- Automate reports generation
- Design reports to be exportable to PDF, Excel and Excel (Data Only) formats

Skills Used: Crystal Reports, Xcelsius, Business Objects